#### https://ewanmorrison.co.uk

# **Ewan Morrison**

I am a motivated full stack software engineer with a passion for the front end. I have a lot of experience working with modern web frameworks including React and Angular. I have also designed backend microservices in C# and NodeJS and have maintained mobile applications. I take great pride in my work and I love being given the responsibility to take ownership of my solutions. As well as this I like to contribute to open source software, and I have quite a few side projects. I'm very open to learning new technologies, especially anything related to functional programming!

# Experience

### Spark Energy September 2019–Present

I am currently working on the **digital team** responsible for the tools to help customers manage their energy accounts. In this role I have worked on creating a **design system** with **bespoke React components** and used this to develop intuitive applications to help enable Spark's customers. I have also **architected build and deployment pipelines** and integrated **end to end testing** solutions.

Another project involved rebuilding the account management portal in React, including a redesign from both a visual and product perspective. I used monitoring platforms to identify problems and improve the quality of our solutions. I felt like I was wearing both a UX and front end engineer hat and I really enjoyed that opportunity.

I also maintained the existing mobile application and began designing the architecture of what would have been its modern replacement. I explored a range of frameworks and weighed up the benefits and disadvantages of different approaches. I made small proof of concepts in both React Native and Flutter. I learnt how to build, deploy and manage apps on the app stores.

#### Craneware July 2018–September 2019

This role exposed me to a wide range of technologies and gave me a great opportunity to hone my skills. I worked on many high impact projects, ranging from implementing a new authentication system for a large product suite, feature delivery, addressing critical security issues to rewriting and enhancing legacy front end code into performant modern Angular.

As part of one project, which had begun during my personal development time, I **led a team of interns** to rewrite legacy front end code, and **liaised with UX and product** to simultaneously **deliver enhancements**. This was a great opportunity to **mentor and nurture** the interns' skills.

When developing new features, I followed the **TDD approach** of starting with unit tests. This provides me with a solid foundation from which I wrote **clean**, **efficient and expressive code**. I enjoy using many features of a range of programming paradigms and I understand the benefits of different approaches. I have read books about **OOP design patterns** and taken courses in **functional programming**, each having a **significant impact on how I write code**.

### Education

### Edinburgh College of Art - Graphic Design Night Class 2020

I took part in a Graphic Design night class to improve my design skills. I learnt about the use of **typography, colour** and covered a lot of the **fundamentals of good design**. It was a very enjoyable class and I've been able to **apply the concepts** I've learnt about here to both my **work and personal projects**.

### The University of Edinburgh - Physics BSc Hons (2:1) 2015-2018

I was awarded an upper second class honours physics degree. My time at university gave me a very solid **grounding in mathematics** and **logical thinking**. It also taught me how to approach problems in **intelligent and novel ways**.

I focused on **programming based classes** and tackled challenges such as efficiently **simulating complex systems** (including a quantum processor), creating **machine learning** based prediction models, and statistical **data analysis**. The majority of my coding was done in **Python**.

### St John's Academy - Secondary School 2009–2015

My achievements at school also include being awarded the **best grades in my year** and winning the **school Dux medal**. I was awarded **3A's at Advanced Higher** and **4A's and a B at Higher** for subjects including Spanish, Physics, and Maths.

# References

References are available upon request.

I can be contacted by **email** at <u>ewanmorrison@hotmail.co.uk</u> or through **my website**. <u>https://ewanmorrison.co.uk</u>